Sunny Singh

me@sunnysingh.io | +1 (516) 537-8258 | 1026 Bent Branch St, Gastonia, NC 28054

Summary

Experienced and passionate web developer with extensive programming and web design skills. I am constantly exploring new technologies in the industry for creating efficient, secure, and pleasant-to-use websites and web applications.

Skills

Programming Languages: SQL/MySQL, PHP, Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js Libraries & Frameworks: Laravel, WordPress, Bootstrap, jQuery, Angular, Ionic, Less/Sass/PostCSS

Software & Tools: Bash/zsh, Git, Vagrant, Adobe Photoshop, Sketch 2, Microsoft Office

Certifications: Microsoft Office Excel 2010, Microsoft Office Access 2010

Experience

Ninjality
Co-founder, Lead Developer
January 2014 - Present
http://ninjality.com

A small web company startup. I worked on client and internal projects including:

- Redesign for <u>Digital Bounds</u>, a technology blog. I was mainly responsible for converting a responsive HTML/CSS layout to a WordPress theme.
- Web app for <u>CodeBee</u>, a social network for developers and designers. Back-end code was done with Laravel, a web framework for PHP. The front-end UI was mainly Bootstrap and jQuery. I also added in real-time features by utilizing Node.js, Redis, and Socket.IO.
- Open source project called <u>socialshares</u>. I wrote it to help other developers fix privacy and performance issues on the web by writing a common set of share buttons. Code is hosted and shared through GitHub and involved front-end (HTML, CSS, JS) technologies.
- Website and mobile app for finding businesses within resort locations. Involved building a location finder, listing search, and admin dashboard for business owners. API created with Laravel, which was used by the Angular front-end for the website, and Ionic for the mobile app.

WIX Filters
Web Marketing, Web Development
June 2012 - Present
Gastonia, NC

- Saved the company thousands of dollars by rebuilding the website's timeline so that it no longer depended on Adobe Flash Player (removing the need to outsource the development).
- Edited product images with Adobe Photoshop by removing backgrounds, adjusting color and saturation, cropping, and exporting to various sizes and formats
- Added, deleted, and updated store locations for the website with Microsoft Access database software.
- Managed users for the online training program, WIX eLearning.

Personal Website Creator August 2011 - Present http://sunnysingh.io

Portfolio-style website to display my skills, projects, articles, and contact information. Recently redesigned with:

- A responsive layout with CSS Flexbox.
- History.pushState API for fluid page transitions.
- Static site/blog generator called Metalsmith, written in Node.js.
- PostCSS and cssnext for processing custom CSS properties and adding fallbacks.
- Webpack and Babel build tools for processing ES2015 (ES6) syntax of JavaScript.
- SVG for logo and icons.
- Optimized performance (96+ rankings in Google Page Speed).

OWL Art Center Website Management April 2009 - 2012 Hewlett, NY

Responsible for continual maintenance of an art gallery company's website such as keeping information up-to-date and creating new pages for artists. Was an already made website, thus it required knowledge of:

- Drupal, a PHP content management system and framework.
- FTP for accessing and uploading files.
- Photoshop for updating schedules.

Relevant Experience

STARS Program Charlotte, NC

Part of the STARS program at UNC Charlotte, designed to allow students to give back to the community of computing. Was given leadership roles in assisting students to learn coding fundamentals such as logic truth tables and basic HTML/CSS.

Education

University of North Carolina at Charlotte

Degree: B.A. in Computer Science Concentration: Web Development Outside Concentration: Business Anticipated Date of Graduation: 2016

References are available upon request.